Guide to the Aaron L. Binenkorb films, ca. 1950-1980.
Binenkorb, Aaron L. films
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Aaron L. Binenkorb films, [ca. 1950-1980]
6689
Binenkorb, Aaron L.
59 reels 16mm film.
Movie film
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Fifty nine films created by Aaron L. Binenkorb documenting travels in Spain, Russia, Sweden, Italy, Singapore, Norway, Greece, Morocco, Holland, India, Australia, Japan, New Zealand, Trinidad, France, Bali, Tahiti, Samoa, South Africa, Denmark, Portugal, and Germany.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Aaron L. Binenkorb was born in 1903 in New York City and grew up in Middletown, New York. Following his graduation from Cornell in 1925, he worked for a furniture company in Buffalo and then as owner/operator of E.L. Tichenor Company, Inc., a wholesale paper supplier based in Middletown. After retiring from his business in 1950, Binenkorb traveled widely on cruise ships and pursued his interests in photography and cinematography by making travel films. From 1960 until 1980, Binenkorb was a port lecturer and showed his films on cruise lines. His film "Disneyland" won an award in an international film competition, and his film about the Pitcairn Islands, "The Lonely Islands," won an award from the Metropolitan Motion Picture Club of New York City.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Fifty nine films created by Aaron L. Binenkorb documenting travels in Spain, Russia, Sweden, Italy, Singapore, Norway, Greece, Morocco, Holland, India, Australia, Japan, New Zealand, Trinidad, France, Bali, Tahiti, Samoa, South Africa, Denmark, Portugal, and Germany.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Binenkorb, Aaron L.
Subjects:
Travel
Places:
Spain -- Description and travel.; Russia -- Description and travel.; Sweden -- Description and travel.; Italy -- Description and travel.; Singapore -- Description and travel.; Norway -- Description and travel.; Greece -- Description and travel.; Morocco -- Description and travel.; Holland -- Description and travel.; India -- Description and travel.; Australia -- Description and travel.; Japan -- Description and travel.; New Zealand -- Description and travel.; Trinidad -- Description and travel.; France -- Description and travel.; Bali -- Description and travel.; Tahiti -- Description and travel.; Samoa -- Description and travel.; South Africa -- Description and travel.; Denmark -- Description and travel.; Portugal -- Description and travel.; Germany -- Description and travel.; Spain; Russia; Sweden; Ithaly; Singapore; Norway; Greece; Morocco; Holland; India; Australia; Japan; New Zealand; Trinidad; France; Bali; Tahiti; Samoa; South Africa; Denmark; Portugal; Germany; Australia; Denmark; France; French Polynesia -- Tahiti (Island); Germany; Greece; India; Italy; Japan; Morocco; Netherlands; New Zealand; Norway; Portugal; Russia; Samoa; Singapore; South Africa; Spain; Sweden; Trinidad and Tobago -- Trinidad
Form and Genre Terms:
Pictorial works
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. 16mm Film
  - Majorca, Gibraltar, Montserrat, 605 (Box 1)
    19 minutes
  - Acapulco, 606 (Box 1)
  - Panama Canal, 607 (Box 1)
    22 minutes
  - Fiji- Suvarewa River, Korolevu, 608 (Box 1)
  - Lisbon, 609 (Box 1)
  - Madeira, with travel guide, 610 (Box 1)
  - Paris, London, 611 (Box 1)
  - The Lonely Islands- Pitcairn Islands. With newspaper clipping., 612 (Box 1)
  - Samoa, Tonga, 613 (Box 1)
  - New Guinea, Guadalcanal. With tour description., 614 (Box 1)
  - Spain- Barcelona, Santiago de Compostello, Montserrat, 615 (Box 2)
  - Hong Kong, 616 (Box 2)
    30 minutes
  - Pitcairn, TV. Pastor William Fagel, 617 (Box 2)
  - Easter Island, Pitcairn, Tristan Da Cunha, Zanzibar, 618 (Box 2)
  - Cirkus Shumann, Copenhagen at night, 619 (Box 2)
  - Stockholm, Helsinki, 620 (Box 2)
  - Russia, 621 (Box 2)
  - New Zealand, Auckland, Rotorua, Wellington, South Island, 622 (Box 2)
  - Holland, Belgium, 623 (Box 3)
  - Singapore, Bali. With tour description, 624 (Box 3)
  - Copenhagen, Odense Folksmuseum, 625 (Box 3)
    40 minutes
  - North Icelands-Iceland, etc. with handwritten notes, 626 (Box 3)
  - Germany- Hamburg, Lubeck, 627 (Box 3)
  - Italy, with map of Florence, 628 (Box 3)
  - Celon, Rhodes, Tunis, Malta, 629 (Box 3)
  - Introducing the New Worker to his Job, 630 (Box 4)
  - Bangkok, 631 (Box 4)
  - Spain- Malaga to Granada, Seville, 632 (Box 4)
  - Morocco- Rabat, Marakesh, Casablanca. With list of sites, 633 (Box 4)
  - Tahiti, Rarotonga, Cook, 634 (Box 4)
  - Carnival Cruise to Rio, 635 (Box 4)
  - Spain- Madrid to Toledo, 636 (Box 4)
  - Funchal- Madeira, 637 (Box 4)
  - Australia, Sydney, Hobart, 10 year skyline contrast, 638 (Box 4)
  - Across the Line Starters- OE389 United World, 639 (Box 4)
  - Greece- Corinth, Athens, Piaeus, 640 (Box 4)
  - Alhoa Land, 641 (Folder O/S)
  - What is Africa?, 642 (Folder O/S)
  - Lisbon, Gibraltar, Santa Cruz, Funchal, Malaga, Tangier, 643 (Folder O/S)
  - Kenya Treetops, 644 (Folder O/S)
  - Hawaii, Poland, Belgium, Copenhagen, 645 (Folder O/S)
  - South Africa, 646 (Folder O/S)
  - Spain- Madrid, Toledo, Malaga, Seville, Grenada, 647 (Folder O/S)
  - Denmark- Copenhagen, Odense, 648 (Folder O/S)
  - India- Bombay, Nasik, Delhi, Agra, Benares, Cobra, Cremations, 649 (Folder O/S)
  - Egypt- Suez, Adan, 650 (Folder O/S)
  - South America, Barbados, Cartagena, Bahia, Neptune, Rio, Montevideo, Buenos Aires, 651 (Folder O/S)
  - Dubrovnik, Venice, 1952-1970; 653 (Folder O/S)
  - Bahia carnival cruise, 1956; 652 (Box 5)
  - South Pacific-Lima, Havana, Panama, New York, 1958; 654 (Box 5)
  - Japan, 1959; 655 (Box 5)
  - Bergen- Oslo, 1962; 656 (Box 5)
  - India- Jaipur, Agra, Delhi, 1968; 657 (Box 5)
  - Japan- Yokahama, Nikko, Kyoto, Nara, 1969; 658 (Box 5)
  - Moscow, 1969; 659 (Box 5)
  - Trinidad Cruise, 1969; 660 (Box 5)
  - Norway, 1969; 661 (Folder O/S)
  - Malta, Turkey, 1973; 662 (Box 5)